WELDING QC COORDINATOR

Conrad Yorke +44 (-0) 1482

210769

20 St. Margarets Close +44 (-0) 741

4093328

Driffield HYPERLINK

"mailto:conradyorke@yahoo.co.uk" Email Me

East Yorkshire **D.O.B 19.05.1965**

Y025 6XX

conradyorke@yahoo.co.uk

.....

Summary of Experience

QA/QC professional with all-round experience in the field of hydrocarbon pipelines, associated fabrications and installations. My main approvals are QC specific – Welding and Coating Inspection (BGAS-CSWIP), coupled with a Level II CSWIP Welding QC Coordinator qualification. I also hold approvals in AUT Interpretation (CSWIP/ASNT LEVEL II) having been trained by the man most consider to be the authority on AUT – ED GINZEL of CANADA. Moreover, I have completed both IRCA Internal and Lead QMS Auditor courses in an effort to strengthen my goal of achieving a position as a QA Manager. I'm interested in developing my career and expertise in the field, especially in the areas of risers, umbilical's, flexibles, design, construction and integrity management and presently working towards a degree in Molecular Science with the Open University.

I am experienced in the reviewing of Procedures, ITP's and Quality Plans and the initiation of all project welding and QA/QC requirements. Postings outside the UK include Spain, Iran, Norway, Holland, Iraq, Germany, Dubai, Abu Dhabi, Russia, China, Angola, Canada, Qatar, Argentina & Kuwait.

, , ,	C	
Positions Held		Project

Vessel Lead/Client Rep	Stealth PLB – Foster Wheeler - Iraq
SCR/Quality Surveillance Lead	RWE - Holland
Client Coating Inspector	Occidental Petroleum - Qatar
Engineering Surveyor	Lloyds Register - Canada
Senior Client Inspector	TGS - Argentina
Offshore Supervisor	EnCana - Canada
QA Advisor	Cameron – Celle, Germany
SCR/Quality Surveillance Lead	Nordstream, Vyksa, Russia
AUT Auditor	Statoil - Iran
Client Coating Inspector	Exxon Mobil – Qatar & Abu Dhabi
Client AUT Interpreter	Med Gaz – Almeria - Spain
Welding Lead	Acergy - Angola
Client Inspector	Ras Gas – Dubai & Qatar

Senior AUT Interpreter	BBL – UK & Netherlands
Main Line Welding & Coating Inspector	Stolt Off Shore – UK & Norway

This is not an exhausted list – many other short term assignments have been completed on lay barges in the capacity of Client Inspector in the disciplines of Welding, Coating and AUT.

Technical Qualifications/Approvals:

CSWIP Level II Welding QC Coordinator	IRCA QMS 9000:2000 Lead Auditor
CSWIP Level II AUT Interpreter/Auditor	IRCA Internal Auditor
BGAS – CSWIP Welding Inspector	ASNT Level II AUT Interpreter/Auditor(Lapsed)
BGAS – CSWIP Coating Inspector	Lloyds Register Approved AUT Interpreter
Medgas Approved AUT Interpreter	BBL Approved AUT Interpreter
H.E.T.A. Welding Approval	

Skills:

Excellent technical knowledge in my field, having covered pipe mills, pipelines and lay-barges in the capacity of QA, QC, Interpreter, Auditor, Client Inspector, Engineering Surveyor and Client Rep/Vessel Lead, passing all the leading course exams for QA/QC Professionals at first instance.

Lab test (Coating) experience with Indentation Resistance, Elongation, Cathodic Disbondment and Flexibility testing alongside of full coating plant/line surveillance of PE, PP, FBE, 3L PE, HDPU, HSS and Cold Applied Laminate Tapes.

Extensive Mechanical Test House experience including DWTT's, CTOD's, Tensile, Bend, Macro, Charpy, Hardness & "Salami" slicing.

Knowledgeable in all aspects of Pipe Mill operations (from Plate Feeding to Final Bench). Experience with Carbon/Carbon low alloy steel, Small Bore Stainless Steel Tubing, Inconel &

CRA pipe.

Extensive knowledge of NDT methods MUT, RT, RTR and AUT Inspection (including Multi-Probe/Phased Array systems – RTD/RD-Tech/SPS/SPS Hybrid & Kraut Kramer). Familiar with SMAW, SAW, FCAW, TIG, GMAW welding (including PWHT), incorporating SATURN, SATURNX, PASSO, PRESTO, CRC, VERMATT and PHEONIX welding systems (single/dual torch, pulsed/short-circuit/spray/S.T.T open root, ALX & ALX2).

Participated in both Shallow & Deep water projects (up to 1500m) in both J & S-Lay mode (including a combined hybrid lay system), including installation of PLET's & PLEM's, Flow Lines, Risers, Offshore Load Lines, Termination Assemblies and Inline Tees (SURF).

Knowledge of pipe barge/marine operations through on the job training and thus familiar with stinger configurations, stress analysis, pipe alignment and related issues.

Familiar with Codes/Standards DNV OS F101, TR1278, API 1104, BS4515, P2/P9, CW 5-6 & AWS D1-1. BS EN Standards 288-9:1999; 3834:2005; 473:2008; 14731:2005; 5817:2007; 287-1:2004. NF-A49-710. (not an exhausted list)

Experience of WPQ's, WQT's, As-Builts/As-Runs, QP's, ITP's & AUT System

Verification and Calibration.

Conversant with QMS/Production Auditing, Kick-off/Daily Production meetings & Electronic Quality and Tracking systems.

Knowledge and experience of safety related issues; safety audits, risk assessments, JSA's, toolbox and permit to work systems. Presently working towards NEBOSH International Diploma in Health and Safety.

Proactive, forward thinking and an excellent communicator.

Good Supervisory / Man Management skills and able to work alone or as part of a team. Computer literate with experience in using MS software suite

Education & Training:

University of Lincoln

1993 - 1996

- 3 year Diploma in Law and Business, including advanced financial accounting, taxation, and quantitative methods

Hull College of Further Education

1992 - 1993

4 A/S levels

Miscellaneous

Basic Offshore Safety Induction Inc E.B.S. (OPITO Approved)	European Combined Survival & Fire fighting (OPITO Approved)
Norwegian Sector Offshore Medical	Yellow Fever Vaccination
UK Off-Shore Medical	H2S Certificate

Career History

Foster Wheeler on behalf of S.O.C – Offshore Iraq Present

July 2011 -

Client Rep/Vessel Lead aboard PLB Stealth, responsible for monitoring activities in relation to the installation and commissioning of two 48" buried parallel pipelines (including all HSE), 10Km onshore and 50Km offshore; Five (5) Shore pull operations, installation of three single point moorings (SPM's) complete with subsea pipeline end manifolds (PLEM's) capable of receiving and loading VLCC tankers; installation of a 600MT subsea valve manifold for directing flow between the existing and future offshore export facilities; dredging works to achieve pipeline burial and sufficient water depth for VLCC's mooring to the SPM's.

Genesis Consulting on behalf of RWE – Holland – May 2011

January 2011

SCR/Quality Surveillance Lead on the Breagh Pipeline Project: a 100 Km 20" export line & a 3" Mono Ethylene Glycol line from the Breagh "A" Platform (block 42/13 Southern North Sea) to the Teeside Gas Processing Facility via a beach value station at Coatham

Sands. Working between Nijmegen and Rotterdam overseeing the coating PQT's, application and testing (3L PE) alongside the WPQ's, WQT's, NDT, Mechanical Testing and AUT Qualification/Validation program for the welding. Review of all Quality Documentation, including ITP's, QP's, Procedures and MRB/Data Books.

Occidental Petroleum of Qatar Ltd – Qatar September 2010 – November 2010

Client Coating Inspector aboard the NPCC PLB 648 for Occidental Petroleum of Qatar.. Full involvement during the final installation phase of infield flow lines and a main oil export line (in the ISND development, Idd Al Shargi Field), offshore Qatar.

Deep Panuke – Canada July 2010 – September 2010

Engineering Surveyor/SCR responsible for overall quality surveillance of offshore installations, comprising subsea umbilical's, risers and flow lines (Surf's) in the Deep Panuke field offshore Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada, for compliance with approved specifications and procedures on behalf of Lloyds Register (representing the certifying authority), with the purpose of reporting upon the integrity of the installed pipeline. This involved 18 km of 8" production flow lines and 2 km of acid gas disposal lines, transporting the produced fluids from the 5 subsea wells to the site of the Production Field Centre (PFC).

Straight of Magellan Pipeline Crossing Project - TGS

Nov 2009

Senior Client Inspector representing TRANSPORTADORA DE GAS DEL SUR S.A. during the Installation of a 36km Pipeline, including landfall at Cape Espiritu Santo in Tierra del Fuego. Responsible for a full team of Inspectors (12) monitoring Welding, Coating, RTR (Real Time Radiography) and TOFD Inspection on behalf of the Client aboard the Solitaire Pipe Lay Vessel.

EnCana - Canada October 2009

July 2009 -

EnCana Offshore Supervisor (overseeing an inspection team of 15) for the Deep Panuke Project, Canada.. This involved the installation of facilities required to produce natural gas from the Deep Panuke field offshore Nova Scotia, an export line of approximately 172 Km being laid by Allseas. Responsible for all QA/QC activities aboard the Lorelay on behalf of EnCana, including welding (Pheonix system), Coating and AUT (SPS Hybrid system).

Cameron - Celle - Germany 2009

Jan - April

QA Advisor on the Total Akpo Project. Responsible for compilation and review of the MRB's for subsea components supplied by Cameron.

Nordstream – Vyksa, Russia 2008

May - Nov

Senior QA/QC Client Quality Representative for the Nordstream project. Responsible for a team of 21 Inspectors at the OMK Steel Works Pipe Mill, Vyksa. Full QA role with

responsibility for all QC activities in both the pipe mill (including full NDT – RTR/AUT) and coating plant (3 Layer Polyethylene and internal Liquid Epoxy Flow Coat).

Medgaz – Almeria, Spain. 2008

Feb - May

Client AUT Interpreter on the Medgaz project, Spain. AUT Surveillance, (Pipe wizard), welding (Passo) and coating (Liquid Epoxy primer & 6mm polypropylene HSS) aboard the Castoro Sei lay-barge for Quad Jointing activities prior to J-lay operations in the Mediterranean.

Ras Gas – Dubai / Qatar 2008

January - Feb

Client Inspector on the Ras Gas expansion project (2 x 38" sour gas pipelines from wellhead 6 to wellhead 7 & 8), offshore Qatar. Responsible for Welding, Coating and AUT (Shaw system) surveillance aboard the DBL 27.

Exxon Mobil - Qatar DBL 750 Nov 2007

May 2007 -

Coating Engineer (Exxon Mobil Off Shore Installation Team).

Requested to join the ExxonMobil Installation team in 2007 – a group of experts within their own particular field – working on major installation projects throughout the world for Exxon – in this case the Qatar gas II Project. Full QA/QC Involvement on the Initial Field Development (IFD) Phase of the Qatar Gas II project. Which encompassed subsea pipelines, cables and tie-ins including CRA 16", 34" and 38" pipe. Monitoring the welding process, (Vermatt welding system/MMA), coating (FBE), AUT (Pipe wizard) and Radiography alongside of Fusion Bonded Epoxy and Polychloroprene corrosion coating with a HDPF Infill.

Independent Specialist Contractor in the field of QA/QC – welding and coating Inspection 2007

2002 -

Assignments include -

Acergy - offshore - Angola 2007 - Apr 2007

Mar

Lead QC Welding Inspector - BP Greater Plutonio Project (Block 18)

Installation phase ("J" and "S" lay) of Subsea Umbilicals, Risers and Flowlines (SURF) in deep water (depths of up to 1500m), off shore Angola. Monitoring the connection and installation of associated flowlines, Offshore Load Lines, Termination Assemblies and Inline Tees (OLL, FTA's and ILT's).

Statoil - Asaloyeah - Iran

Oct

Statoil Internal AUT 2nd Party Auditor - South Pars Gas Field Dev. (Phase 8)

Internal AUT Audit on behalf of the client to assess the quality of the 3rd party NDT Company (RTD of Netherlands) in relation to the Automated Ultrasonic Testing of welded

joints (Multi-Probe system).

Balgzand NL (BBL) - Castoro Sei 2006 - Sept 2006

June

Lloyds Register Client Representative.

Chosen as Lead AUT Inspector for the BBL Project May 2006

3rd Party Inspector aboard the C6 for the Balgzand to Bacton pipeline system, approximately 230km, exporting natural gas from the Netherlands to the UK crossing the North Sea continental Shelf. Duties were confined to monitoring Saipem personnel in the three disciplines of Welding (Passo system), Coating and AUT (Pipe wizard). Responsible for AUT system verification and M/L Interpretation and one of only two professionals to pass both the BBL and Lloyds Register exams in AUT Interpretation, Italy 2006.

Saipem - Qatar Castoro Sei

Jan

2006 - May 2006

QC Welding and Coating Inspector.

Full QC involvement on the Dolphin Project, off shore Qatar, for the Contractor, Saipem. Duties included but were not confined to, Coating Inspection of Canusa HSS, Sea Sleeve and Infill Medium (Granular Marine Mastic), Welding Inspection (Passo welding system), Coat and Wrap Operator Qualification Tests and Welder Qualification Tests.

Stolt Offshore - LB200 2005 - Nov 2005

Feb

QC Welding and Coating Inspector.

Main Line Inspector with full quality control involvement on the Langeled Project, the foremost subsea pipelay in the world at present. Monitoring welding (Saturnax/Saturn Serima Dasa welding system) and coating activities aboard the LB 200 (HSS, HDPF & CWC).

Kingland Group Petroleum, Gas Pipeline Co, China 2004 - Jan 2005

Oct

QA/QC Inspector

Ensuring all specified and relevant materials and quality production documentation was evidentially produced at the end of the project.

Working to API 5L

Democratic Republic Congo (Point Noire) 2004 - Mar 2004

Jan

Welding and Coating Inspector

Overseeing the fabrication of spool pieces for the production platform named 'East Kocongo'. monitoring both Welding and Coating activities (FBE).

Oil and Pipeline Agency, Bristol 2003 - Aug 2003

Apr

Welding and Coating Inspector

Project involved the refurbishment of a fuel pumping station at Portishead near Bristol. Duties included welding inspection of fabricated spool pieces (numerous welds on 6 inch, 8 inch and 10 inch pipes).

British Gas Pipeline, Hull, Yorkshire Sep2002 - Nov 2002 Back End Welding Inspector for Cross Country Pipeline

Duties included the inspection of the capping and any repairs completed.

Easington Gas Terminal, Humberside 2002 - Sep 2002

Jul

Welding and Coating Inspector - British Gas, Ambergate

Duties included welding and coating inspection and Welder Qualification. Tests (WQT's), coupled with Radiographic Interpretation prior to client inspection.

Oil and Pipeline Agency (OPA) 2002 - May 2002

Apr

Welding and Coating Inspector

Duties included welding and coating inspection, ensuring contractor adherence to specification and all associated paperwork.

